Tommaso Cortonesi

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT · TEAM | FADER

□ (+39) 3288731860 | ■tommaso.cortonesi@gmail.com | • j4bberwocky | • tommaso-cortonesi

Summary

Current Solution Architect and Team Leader at Engineering Ingegneria Informatica SPA. 10+ years experience specializing in backend and web development in Java environment (JEE and Spring ecosystem), 5+ years experience in leading dev team. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, in architect, design, test and develop the best solution for the customer needs and learning new technologies and tools.

Work Experience _____

Municipality of Florence Florence

SOLUTION ARCHITECT

· Architect, design and develop integration components and web app to manage building and environmental practices

- Lead a team of 4 people
- Estimate, plan and share teams activities
- Technologies: Maven, Spring ecosystem, Primefaces, SVN, Docker, Activiti, Alfresco

Mediolanum Bank

Milan, Italy

Senior Solution Developer 2015 - 2019

- Analysis, design, develop web applications for bank promoters (on investment and insurance products)
- Lead a team of 8 people that was in charge of application Management and new feature develop
- Estimate and plan activities, providing technical support
- Train the other team's members on the technologies in use
- Technologies: JSP, EJB 3.0, WebLogic 10, Jenkins, Git

Municipality of Milan Milan, Italy

 SOLUTION DEVELOPER
 2013 - 2015

- · Develop, mantain and support of a web application that manages registrations to nursery schools and kindergartens
- · Technologies: JSP, Tomcat, Ant, SVN

Monte dei Paschi di Siena Bank

Siena, Italy

2019 - present

JUNIOR SOLUTION DEVELOPER

2010 - 2013

- Develop of backend components (EJB) inside a SOA architecture for bank transfer services
- Technologies: EJB 3.0, Spring, JBoss, MyBatis, WebSphere AS, SVN

Education

2020/22 Associate Cloud Engineer, Google Cloud Certified

2020 **Pivotal Certified Spring Professional**, Pivotal Software, Inc.

2019/22 AWS Certified Developer - Associate, Amazon Web Service

2017 Certified Java EE 6 Enterprise Architect, Oracle Certified Master

2006/09 M.S. in Mathematics, University of Siena, Italy (IT)

 $2003/2006 \ \textbf{B.S. in Mathematics}, \ \textbf{University of Siena, Italy (IT)}$

Skills_

Programming Java, Go, Python, TEX

Back-end Java EE, Spring ecosystem, Django, REST API **DevOps** AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Google Cloud Platform

Soft skills Empathy, strong communication skills and ability to work within also a distributed team

Languages Italian, English